## John Williams

9753656492 · deesha2@gmail.com · www.andreykurenkov.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Microsoft and Google certified Data Scientist with eight years of experience. Looking to increase data efficiency for Contranix Capital Inc. Achievements include developing data regression models to predict company stock prices with 30% higher accuracy than the historical average. Achieved 25% improvement in investment returns across all clients. Extremely skilled in machine learning, data visualization, and creative thinking.

### **SKILLS**

Microsoft Excel, Minitab, QlikView, SQL, Tableau, SPSS, SAS, XML, KNIME, Google Analytics, Python, Splunk, Apache Spark, RTL, R Shiny, Pivot Tables, Hyper Research, HTML, C++

### **EDUCATION**

**BSc in Statistics** 

Cambridge University

Courses: Probability and Statistics, Generalized Linear Models, Applied Statistics

- Average GPA of 4.7
- Academic Excellence in Computer Studies and Technical Sciences
- Excelled in machine learning and data science coursework.
- President, AI club

# Maria College

Department of Computer Science

- Average GPA of 4.5 for 2 Consecutive Years
- Member of the Volleyball Team

**GRE**: quantitative 169/170 (99<sup>th</sup> percentile), verbal 165/170 (96<sup>th</sup> percentile), writing 5.0/6.0 (95<sup>th</sup> percentile)

**MOOC**: Coursera – Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Programming Languages, IBM data science, Tableau

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Data Scientist at Citibank**, Seattle January 2021 — Present

Main responsibility is to develop and implement a machine learning tool that computed adjusted P/E values for the new business section of the bank, assisting with better due diligence processes.

- Fulfilled all data science responsibilities for a high-end capital management firm.
- Developed and presented models for potential holdings to fund managers. Achieved 25% better returns vs. previous performance.
- Predicted stock price 27% better than traditional figures.
- Provide technical leadership for a team that designs and develops analysis systems to extract meaning from large scale data.
- Mentor high-end organizations on large scale data and analytics using advanced statistical and machine learning models.

### Data Scientist at HSBC, Macau January 2019 — January 2021

Worked as a Data Scientist in a capital management firm with the purpose of performing big data analytics and design prediction models to ascertain future client retention trends against those of competition firms

- Developed and presented models for potential holdings.
- Implemented machine learning tools to compute adjusted PE values.
- Fulfilled all data science duties for a high-end capital management firm.
- Develop a customer segmentation algorithm in R that scores sales leads for jets and increases market share.
- Apply logistic regression models to jet maintenance records that predict jet sales based on aircraft usage and maintenance type.

### Junior Data Scientist at Nedbank, January 2017 — December 2019

- Be responsible for implementing data mining and statistical machine learning solutions to combat various business problems such as sales lead scoring, demand forecasting, supply chain optimization, and targeted marketing.
- Develop a customer segmentation algorithm in R that scores sales leads for jets and increases market share.